<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<survey>
  <title>
    PROPOSED BEST PRACTICE GUIDELINES TO CLARIFY THE MEANING OF
    “NONCOMMERCIAL” IN THE CREATIVE COMMONS LICENSES
  </title>
  <screens>
    <screen>
      <title>Welcome to the NC survey</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    <![CDATA[

<p>This NonCommercial survey is based on
<a
href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/DiscussionDraftNonCommercial_Guidelines">the
current discussion draft of the “NonCommercial Guidelines”</a> that
were posted to the Creative Commons weblog and the cc-licenses list on
January 6, 2006.  The purpose of this survey is to get your feedback
on what qualifies as a noncommercial use under the Creative Commons
licenses that include a “NonCommercial” license limitation
(specifically, the Attribution-NonCommercial license, the
Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike license, and the
Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives license.</p>

<p>To complete this survey, please click the “Next” button below.
The survey generally takes no more than 5 minutes to complete.  To
navigate back to an earlier question, please use the “Back” button
provided at the bottom of each survey page.  Do not try to navigate by
using “Back” button of your browser.</p>

<p>When you reach a conclusion page of the survey (i.e., one that
tells you whether or not the proposed use is a commercial or
noncommercial use), you will have the option of providing us with
comments on the survey result.  You need to click the “Submit”
button so that we receive these comments.</p>
]]>
	    </title>
	  </question>
	</questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section A: Your use of this survey</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Have you applied one or more of the following Creative
	    Commons licenses to your work — Attribution-NonCommercial,
	    Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike,
	    Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives?
	    </title>
	  <option onselect="Section A: Your use of this survey (a)">Yes</option>
	  <option onselect="Section A: Your use of this survey (b)">No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <!-- This "a" version is for "Yes, applied is true" -->
      <!-- Both yes and no, therefore, can continue on to the next section -->
      <title>Section A: Your use of this survey (a)</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Have you used a work that is licensed under one or more of
	    the following Creative Commons licenses to your work —
	    Attribution-NonCommercial, Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike,
	    Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="Section B">Yes</option>
	  <option onselect="Section B">No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <!-- This "b" version is for "No, applied is false" -->
      <!-- "Yes", therefore, can continue on to the next section -->
      <!-- but "No" has to have us ask "Why are you here?" -->
      <title>Section A: Your use of this survey (b)</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Have you used a work that is licensed under one or more of
	    the following Creative Commons licenses to your work —
	    Attribution-NonCommercial, Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike,
	    Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="Section B">Yes</option>
	  <option>No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section A: Your use of this survey</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>

	    <![CDATA[
<p>	    
	    If you are not a licensee or licensor of a Creative
	    Commons license that contains a NonCommercial license
	    limitation, can you provide some reasons as to why you are
	    completing this survey?

</p>
            <textarea name="why-submitting-comments" cols="20" rows="8"></textarea>

	    ]]>
	    </title>
	  </question>
	</questions>
      </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section B: Nature of the user</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    <![CDATA[

	    Is the person making a use of an NC-licensed work an “allowable NC user” under
	    the noncommercial license condition?  Allowable NC users
	    are:
<ol type="a">
<li>an individual,</li>
<li>a nonprofit educational     institution/library,</li>
<li>a Nonprofit organization as defined
	    under US1 or equivalent law, (together with (1) and (2)
	    “allowable NC users”), or</li>
<li>A commercial copy shop, ISP, search engine, content aggregator, blog aggregator site or similar service provider who, in the course of providing a service
	    at the direction of the allowable NC user, may exercise a
	    right licensed under the Creative Commons license.</li>

]]>
	  </title>
	  <option>Yes</option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>Section C. Nature of the use: Advertising</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the NC-licensed content being used in an advertisement
	    for third party products or services?  For example, Brian’s CC BY-NC licensed photo of the Eiffel Tower being used to advertise bottled water made by Shaun’s company.
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">Yes</option>
	  <option>No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>Section C. Nature of the use: Advertising</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is viewing of an advertisement for third party products or
	    services required as a condition of accessing or viewing
	    the NC-licensed content (eg. “click-through”
	    advertising)?  For example, in order to view Mary’s CC BY-NC-ND licensed article, does a person first see an advertisement for a car.
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">Yes</option>
	  <option>No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>Section C. Nature of the use: Advertising</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the NC-licensed work being used in connection with
	    advertisements for third party products or services where
	    the NC-licensed work is the primary draw or a is
	    substantial amount, both qualitatively and quantitatively?  For example, a podcast consisting solely of CC BY-NC-SA licensed music have ads for a record store at the start and end of the podcast.
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">Yes</option>
	  <option>No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>
	Section D. Conditions on Use: For Services Provided
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands in exchange for a service provided
	    in connection with the NC-licensed work?  For example, a copy shop charging for the service of making a copy or a search engine receiving ad revenue for ads served up when searching for NC-licensed content.
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="Is money changing hands for a service being provided to">
	    Yes
	  </option>
	  <!-- check with Mia -->	    <option onselect="Section E">
	    No
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>
	Section D. Conditions on Use: For Services Provided
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands for a service being provided to
	    (in the case of, for example, a for-profit copy shop) or
	    by an allowable NC user incidental to the use of the
	    NC-licensed work (e.g., course packs provided by an
	    educational institutions)?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use"> 
	    Yes
	  </option>
	  <option>
	    No
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section E. Money
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands in relation to use of the work?
	    </title>
	  <option onselect="Section F">
	    In connection with verbatim use of an NC-licensed work
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="Section G">
	    In connection with derivative use of an NC-licensed work
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use">Not at all</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section F. Conditions on Use: Original Work
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands as a condition of using the
	    NC-licensed work (e.g., by levying a direct charge or
	    charging subscription fees for access to NC-licensed
	    work(s))?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">
	    Yes
	  </option>
	  <option>
	    No
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>
	Section F. Conditions on Use: Original Work
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands as a condition of using another
	    work that includes an NC-licensed work, where the
	    NC-licesned work is either the primary draw or a
	    substantial amount, whether qualitatively or
	    quantitatively (e.g., where an NC-licensed image is used
	    on the cover of and as a central part of a book that is
	    sold commercially)?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">
	    Yes
	  </option>
	  <option>
	    No
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>
	Section F. Conditions on Use: Original Work
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands as a condition of using
	    another work that inclues verbatim NC-licensed work,
	    where the NC-licensed work is not the primary draw or is
	    an insubstantial amount, both qualitatively and quantitatively,
	    as long as there is no charge for accessing the NC-licensed work
	    (e.g., where one NC-licensed image is used in a book that is sold commercially)
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="Provided that there is no charge associated with diectly accessing the work">
	    Yes
	  </option>
	  <option>
	    No
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section F. Conditions on Use: Original Work
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands as an optional contribution (e.g.,
	    a tip jar, donations, membership drive) for an allowed NC user that uses the verbatim NC-licensed work or another
	    work that includes a verbatim NC-licensed work?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use">
	    Yes
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use">
	    No
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>
	Section G. Conditions on Use: Derivative Works
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Does the work use a ShareAlike license condition?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="Does the creation of derivative works">Yes</option>
	  <option onselect="Is the money changing hands">No</option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>
	Section G. Conditions on Use: Derivative Works with the Share-Alike condition
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is there any money changing hands in any one of the
	    following ways in connection with the verbatim use of the
	    SA-NC licensed derivative work?
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">
	    As a condition of using the SA-NC-licensed derivative work
	    (e.g., by levying a direct charge or charging subscription
	    fees for access to SA-NC-licensed derivative work(s))
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">
	    As a condition of using another work that includes an
	    SA-NC-licensed derivative work, where the SA-NC-licensed
	    derivative work is either the primary draw or a
	    substantial amount, whether qualitatively or
	    quantitatively (e.g., where a SA-NC-licensed derivative
	    image is used on the cover of and as a central part of a
	    book that is sold commercially)
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="Provided that there is no charge associated with directly accessing the work">
	    As a condition of using another work that includes a
	    verbatim SA-NC-licensed derivative work, where the
	    SA-NC-licensed derivative work is not the primary draw or
	    is an insubstantial amount, both qualitatively and
	    quantitatively, as long as there is no charge for
	    accessing the SA-NC-licensed derivative work (e.g., where
	    one SA-NC-licensed derivative image is used in a book that
	    is sold commercially and the image is not a thematically
	    significant part of the book)
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use">
	    As an optional contribution (e.g., a tip jar, donations,
	    membership drive) for an allowed NC user (diverges from
	    PDF!) that uses the SA-NC-licensed derivative work or
	    another work that includes a SA-NC-licensed derivative
	    work
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>Section G. Conditions on Use: Derivative Works</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the money changing hands in connection with a
	    derivative use of an NC licensed work?  Money can change
	    hands one of these three ways; select the one most
	    appropriate to your use.
	  </title>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a Commercial Use">
	    As a condition of using a derivative work based on an
	    NC-licensed work, of which the original NC-licensed work
	    is the primary draw or a substantial amount, whether
	    qualitatively or quantitatively, of that derivative work
	    (eg. where a commercially released short film is made using a CC BY-NC licensed piece of music and the music is the sole audio component of the film)
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use">
	    As a condition of using a derivative work based on an
	    NC-licensed work, of which the original NC-licensed work
	    is not the primary draw or is an insubstantial amount,
	    both qualitatively and quantitatively, of that derivative
	    work
	    (e.g., a commercially released mash-up is made of a piece of CC BY-NC licensed music that is used only incidentally in the mash-up)
	  </option>
	  <option onselect="The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use">
	    As an optional contribution (e.g. a tip jar, donations,
	    membership drive) for an allowed NC user that uses the
	    verbatim NC-licensed work or another work that includes a
	    verbatim NC-licensed work
	  </option>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen isfinal="yes">
      <title>The proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>

	    <![CDATA[
<p>
	    		  Based on
		  the responses you gave, under the <a
		  href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/DiscussionDraftNonCommercial_Guidelines">current Discussion Draft of the NonCommercial Guidelines</a>,
		  the proposed use would be a non-commercial
		  and permitted under either the Attribution-NonCommercial, Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike and Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives licenses.

                  You may use the "back" button to
		  return to the questions, or you may use the "submit" button to
		  submit your answers to us with comments.
</p>

                   <p>Do you agree or disagree with these results?  Let us know your comments about the survey.</p>
                   <p>If you would like to specify more details about your particular case, please use the box below.</p>

		      <textarea name="does-qualify-comments" cols="20" rows="8"></textarea>

]]>
	    </title>
	  </question>
	</questions>
      </screen>

    <screen isfinal="yes">
      <title>The proposed use would be a Commercial Use (license violation)</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>

	    <![CDATA[
<p>
	    		  Based on
		  the responses you gave, under the <a
		  href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/DiscussionDraftNonCommercial_Guidelines">current Discussion Draft of the NonCommercial Guidelines</a>,
		  the proposed use would be a commercial use and <strong>not</strong> permitted under the terms of the Attribution-NonCommercial, Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike and Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives licenses.</p>

<p>
                  You may use the "back" button to
		  return to the questions, or you may use the "submit" button to
		  submit your answers to us with comments.
</p>


                   <p>Do you agree or disagree with these results?  Let us know your comments about the survey.</p>

                   <p>If you would like to specify more details about your particular case, please use the box below.</p>

		      <textarea name="does-not-qualify--comments" cols="20" rows="8"></textarea>
]]>
	    </title>
	  </question>
	</questions>
      </screen>

    <screen isfinal="yes">
      <title>Provided that there is no charge associated with directly accessing the work, the proposed use would be a NonCommercial Use</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>

	    <![CDATA[
<p>
	    		  Based on
		  the responses you gave, under the <a
		  href="http://lists.ibiblio.org/pipermail/cc-licenses/attachments/20060110/02d7a271/NonCommercialGuidelinesclean-0001.pdf">current Discussion Draft of the NonCommercial Guidelines</a>,
		  the proposed use would be a non-commercial
		  and permitted under either the Attribution-NonCommercial, Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike and Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives licenses <em>provided that there is no charge associated with directly accessing the work</em>.

                  You may use the "back" button to
		  return to the questions, or you may "submit" to
		  submit your answers to us with comments.
</p>

                   <p>Do you agree or disagree with these results?  Let us know your comments about the survey.</p>
                   <p>If you would like to specify more details about your particular case, please use the box below.</p>

		      <textarea name="does-qualify-provided-gratis-comments" cols="20" rows="8"></textarea>

]]>
	    </title>
	  </question>
	</questions>
      </screen>
  </screens>
</survey>
