<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<survey>
  <title>
    PROPOSED BEST PRACTICE GUIDELINES TO CLARIFY THE MEANING OF
    “NONCOMMERCIAL” IN THE CREATIVE COMMONS LICENSES
  </title>
  <screens>
    <screen>
      <title>Section A: Nature of the user</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the user an “allowable NC user” under the noncommercial
	    license condition?  Allowable NC users are: (a) an
	    individual, (b) a nonprofit educational
	    institution/library, (c) Nonprofit organization as defined
	    under US1 or equivalent law, (together with (1) and (2)
	    “allowable NC users”), or (d) A copy shop, ISP or similar
	    service provider who, in the course of providing a service
	    at the direction of the allowable NC user, may exercise a
	    right licensed under the Creative Commons license.
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option>Yes</option>
	    <option onchoose="fail">No</option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section B. Nature of the use: Advertising</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the NC-licensed content being used in an advertisement
	    for third party products or services?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onchoose="fail">Yes</option>
	    <option>No</option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section B. Nature of the use: Advertising</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is viewing of an advertisement for third party products or
	    services required as a condition of accessing or viewing
	    the NC-licensed content (eg. “click-through”
	    advertising)?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onchoose="fail">Yes</option>
	    <option>No</option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section B. Nature of the use: Advertising</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the NC-licensed work being used in connection with
	    advertisements for third party products or services where
	    the NC-licensed work is the primary draw or a is
	    substantial amount, both qualitatively and quantitatively?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onchoose="fail">Yes</option>
	    <option>No</option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section C. Conditions on Use: For Services Provided
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands in exchange for a service provided
	    in connection with the NC-licensed work?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option>
	      Yes
	    </option>
	    <option onchoose="Section D">
	      No
	    </option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section C. Conditions on Use: For Services Provided
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is money changing hands for a service being provided to
	    (in the case of, for example, a for-profit copy shop) or
	    by an allowable NC user incidental to the use of the
	    NC-licensed work (e.g. course packs provided by an
	    educational institutions)?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onchoose="success">
	      Yes
	    </option>
	    <option>
	      No
	    </option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section D. Conditions on Use: Original Work
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	      Is there any money changing hands in connection with the
	      use of the NC licensed work?
	      Money may change hands in connection with the use of an
	      NC-licensed work in at least four ways:
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onchoose="fail">
	      As a condition of using the NC-licensed work
	    </option>
	    <option onchoose="fail">
	      As a condition of using another work that includes an
	      NC-licensed work, where the NC-licensed work is either
	      the primary draw or a substantial amount (whether
	      qualitatively or quantitatively) of the primary draw
	    </option>
	    <option> <!-- check with Mia --> As a condition of using
	    another work that includes a verbatim NC-licensed work,
	    where the NC-licensed work is not the primary draw or is
	    an insubstantial amount, both qualitatively and
	    quantitatively, as long as there is no charge for
	    accessing the NC-licensed work
	    </option>
	    <option> <!-- check with Mia -->
	      As an optional contribution (e.g., a tip jar, donations,
	      membership drive) for an allowed NC user (diverges from
	      PDF!) that uses the verbatim NC-licensed work or another
	      work that includes a verbatim NC-licensed work
	    </option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>
	Section E. Conditions on Use: Derivative Works
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Does the work use a ShareAlike license condition?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onselect="Does the creation of derivative works">Yes</option>
	    <option onselect="Is the money changing hands">No</option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>

    <screen>
      <title>Section E. Conditions on Use: Derivative Works
      </title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Does the creation of derivative works match with the terms
	    given in Section D?
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option>Yes</option>
	    <option>No</option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
    
    <screen>
      <title>Section E. Conditions on Use: Derivative Works</title>
      <questions>
	<question>
	  <title>
	    Is the money changing hands in connection with a
	    derivative use of an NC licensed work?  Money can change
	    hands one of these four ways; select the one most
	    appropriate to your use.
	  </title>
	  <options>
	    <option onselect="fail">
	      As a condition of using a derivative work based on an
	      NC-licensed work, of which the original NC-licensed work
	      is the primary draw or a substantial amount, whether
	      qualitatively or quantitatively, of that derivative work
	    </option>
	    <option onselect="succeed">
	      As a condition of using a derivative work based on an
	      NC-licensed work, of which the original NC-licensed work
	      is not the primary draw or is an insubstantial amount,
	      both qualitatively and quantitatively, of that derivative
	      work
	    </option>
	    <option onselect="succeed">
	      As an optional contribution (e.g., a tip jar, donations,
	      membership drive) for an allowed NC user (DIVERGES FROM
	      PDF!) that uses the derivative work based on the
	      NC-licensed work
	    </option>
	  </options>
	</question>
      </questions>
    </screen>
  </screens>
</survey>
